{
    "id": "aebed4c668a54a8f9abb3842a2e7cd55",
    "title": "Conjunctions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She went to the store …………………… bought some pens.",
            "description": "And is a conjunction. ",
            "answers": [
                "and",
                "so",
                "hence"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I went to her home, ………………………. she was not there.",
            "description": "Use but to connect two contrasting ideas. ",
            "answers": [
                "but",
                "and",
                "so"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "It is raining, ……………………… we have to cancel the picnic.",
            "description": "So shows the effect. Hence is not a conjunction. ",
            "answers": [
                "and",
                "so",
                "hence"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… it was snowing, we went out.",
            "description": "We use though to connect two contrasting ideas. But goes in the middle of the two clauses connected by it. ",
            "answers": [
                "Though",
                "But",
                "Even if"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Will you wait for me ………………………. I finish cooking?",
            "description": "Until shows time. ",
            "answers": [
                "as long as",
                "until",
                "up to"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She was upset …………………………. she had failed her exam.",
            "description": "Because shows the reason. ",
            "answers": [
                "because",
                "so",
                "though"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. I had the money, I could buy a car.",
            "description": "If expresses a condition. ",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "Whether",
                "As"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t know ……………………….. I can help or not.",
            "description": "Either could be used here however, whether is preferred in a formal style. ",
            "answers": [
                "whether",
                "if",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… you need help, just give me a call.",
            "description": "To express a condition, we use if. As shows the reason. ",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "As",
                "Whether"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………… it is expensive, I will buy it.",
            "description": "Either even if or though is possible here with slightly different meanings. ",
            "answers": [
                "Even if",
                "If",
                "Though"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. we heard the news, we rushed to their home.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "As soon as",
                "As long as",
                "No sooner"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. my friends were there, none of them came forward to help me.",
            "description": "Either though or even though is possible here. Even though is a more emphatic form of though.",
            "answers": [
                "Though",
                "Even though",
                "Even if"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}